<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qas on Ivan V</title>
    <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qas on Ivan V</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru-ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grokking the System Design Interview</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/grokking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/grokking/</guid>
      <description>Why System Design Interviews? System Design Interviews: A step by step guide Designing a URL Shortening service like TinyURL Designing Pastebin Designing Instagram Designing Dropbox Designing Facebook Messenger Designing Twitter Designing Youtube or Netflix Designing Typeahead Suggestion Designing an API Rate Limiter Designing Twitter Search Designing a Web Crawler Designing Facebook’s Newsfeed Designing Yelp or Nearby Friends Designing Uber backend Design Ticketmaster (New) System Design Basics  Load Balancing Caching Sharding or Data Partitioning Indexes Proxies Queues Redundancy and Replication SQL vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions. Part 3</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions-3/</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous:  What are the default ports used for SMTP,DNS,FTP,DHCP,SSH?
 SMTP - 25 DNS - 53 FTP- 20(data transfer), 21(connection established) DHCP- 67/UDP(dhcp server) , 68/UDP(dhcp client) SSH - 22    How to check default route and routing table?
 netstat –listen lsof -i    Describe branching strategies you have used?
 Feature branching - keeps all of the changes for a particular feature inside of a branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions. Part 1</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions-1/</guid>
      <description>Questions from chassing/linux-sysadmin-interview-questions Inspired by collection of Linux SysAdm/DevOps interview questions with my answers
General Questions:  What function does DNS play on a network?
 The first place your computer looks is its local DNS cache, which stores information that your computer has recently retrieved. If the information is not stored locally, your computer queries (contacts) your ISP’s recursive DNS servers. If the recursive servers don’t have the answer, they query the root nameservers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions. Part 2</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions-2/</guid>
      <description>Hard Linux Questions:  What is a tunnel and how you can bypass a http proxy?
 A tunnel is a mechanism used to ship a foreign protocol across a network that normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t support it. Tunneling protocols allow you to use, for example, IP to send another protocol in the &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; portion of the IP datagram. Most tunneling protocols operate at layer 4 (Transport), which means they are implemented as a protocol that replaces something like TCP or UDP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>