<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qas on Ivan V</title>
    <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qas on Ivan V</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru-ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 20:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Preparation</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 20:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/interview/</guid>
      <description>Q&amp;amp;A  test-your-sysadmin-skills - A collection of *nix Sysadmin Test Questions and Answers
 Вопросы на собеседовании на позицию DevOps-инженера - неплохой список, можно себе по памяти проверить. Потом дополнить
 What happens when you type google.com into your browser and press enter?
 What happens when I type kubectl run?
 system-design-primer - Learn how to design large-scale systems
   Linux questions
 Grokking
  SRE Interview  Preparing the SRE interview</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grokking the System Design Interview</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/grokking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/grokking/</guid>
      <description>Why System Design Interviews? System Design Interviews: A step by step guide Designing a URL Shortening service like TinyURL Designing Pastebin Designing Instagram Designing Dropbox Designing Facebook Messenger Designing Twitter Designing Youtube or Netflix Designing Typeahead Suggestion Designing an API Rate Limiter Designing Twitter Search Designing a Web Crawler Designing Facebook’s Newsfeed Designing Yelp or Nearby Friends Designing Uber backend Design Ticketmaster (New) System Design Basics  Load Balancing Caching Sharding or Data Partitioning Indexes Proxies Queues Redundancy and Replication SQL vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/questions/</guid>
      <description>Questions from chassing/linux-sysadmin-interview-questions Inspired by collection of Linux SysAdm/DevOps interview questions with my answers
General Questions:  What are the default ports used for SMTP,DNS,FTP,DHCP,SSH?
 SMTP - 25 DNS - 53 FTP- 20(data transfer), 21(connection established) DHCP- 67/UDP(dhcp server) , 68/UDP(dhcp client) SSH - 22    What function does DNS play on a network?
 The first place your computer looks is its local DNS cache, which stores information that your computer has recently retrieved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>