<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qas on Ivan</title>
    <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qas on Ivan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ru-ru</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nice to learn</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/nice-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/nice-learn/</guid>
      <description>База программиста от Egor Biriukov База&#xA;https://www.coursera.org/learn/programming-languages — прекрасная серия из трех курсов про разные парадигмы языков программирования и как они подходят к решению проблем. Помогает снять ООП-блок и понять, что никаких чудес ООП не делает и никаких уникальных проблем не решает.&#xA;Алгоритмы&#xA;Dasgupta, Papadimitriou, Vazirani — текстбук, которому удается не удариться в излишнюю академичность и энциклопедичность. Ничего особого от книги ждать не стоит, решать литкод она не научит, но зияющие дыры в образовании закроет.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion/money</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/promotion-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/promotion-money/</guid>
      <description>https://t.me/c/1336907549/111&#xA;Как говорить о зарплате? Ну приходишь к тимлиду, заходишь справа, под рабочую руку, так что б не достать, приседаешь, так что б смотреть снизу вверх, три раза плюнешь через левое плечо и говоришь: я год закрываю пул реквесты, работаю хорошо, а вы все тут тупые. Дай денег!&#xA;Нет? Ладно, давай тогда представь что ты на свидании.&#xA;Дано: мальчики любят секс, девочки любят секс, все тут ради секса (как минимум на первых порах) и все всё понимают.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview Advices</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/interview-advices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/interview-advices/</guid>
      <description>Вам нужно знать следующее: Arrays, Maps / Dictionaries, Stack, Heap, Trees, Graphs, Linked List. Еще хорошо бы знать алгоритм построения Trie, так как он используется в некоторых задачах.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t go too deep into algorithms. You&amp;rsquo;ll never be asked to write a suffix tree or a balanced tree, or even Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s shortest path algorithm. You need to know the following algorithms: sorting (quick, merge, counting, radix -sort algorithms), binary search, DFS, BFS, DSU (might be useful, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty easy data structure), stacks, min/max stack, queues, heaps, linked lists, KMP, hashes (Rabin-Karp).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview Preparation</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/interview/</guid>
      <description>Lists Tech Interview Handbook interviews - Everything you need to know to get the job. Short description of data structuress FAANG Interview. Бортовые заметки сообщества - docs.google.com Полезные ресурсы для международной карьеры в tech - docs.google.com General Advices А как собеседоваться в 2023? vas3k.club&#xA;Чем можно пользоваться для составления / валидации резюме (в самой статье хороший пример):&#xA;https://www.careercup.com/resume - как должно выглядеть американское резюме https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/resume/ - советы от автора blind 75 https://resumeworded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang Questions</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/go-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/go-questions/</guid>
      <description>Вопросы и ответы для собеседования Go-разработчика *Часть I. Базовые&#xA;*Часть II. Что там с конкурентностью?&#xA;Популярные задачи для собеседований бэкенд-разработчиков на Go и их решения&#xA;Співбесіда з Go. 200+ запитань для Junior, Middle, Senior&#xA;Коллеги, вы меня огорчаете&#xA;Go — 100 вопросов/заданий с собеседований&#xA;Junior Software engineering Какие бывают области памяти программы? В чем их особенности и отличия?&#xA;stack - ограниченный размер, диамически растет для goroutines heap - требует работу GC Расскажите, что вы знаете о HTTP-протоколе, какие составные части запроса?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grokking the System Design Interview</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/grokking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/grokking/</guid>
      <description>Why System Design Interviews? System Design Interviews: A step by step guide Designing a URL Shortening service like TinyURL Designing Pastebin Designing Instagram Designing Dropbox Designing Facebook Messenger Designing Twitter Designing Youtube or Netflix Designing Typeahead Suggestion Designing an API Rate Limiter Designing Twitter Search Designing a Web Crawler Designing Facebook’s Newsfeed Designing Yelp or Nearby Friends Designing Uber backend Design Ticketmaster (New) System Design Basics Load Balancing Caching Sharding or Data Partitioning Indexes Proxies Queues Redundancy and Replication SQL vs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Tools and Instructions: Explanation of everything you can see in htop/top on Linux Linux tracing systems &amp;amp; how they fit together A small handbook about Linux debuggin tools 6 шагов загрузки Linux на пальцах Процессы в Linux Understanding Processes on Linux Учебник. Язык обработки структурированных текстов AWK Linux Performance Analysis in 60,000 Milliseconds My First 5 Minutes On A Server; Or, Essential Security for Linux Servers Debugging Software Deployments with strace The Definitive Guide to Linux System Calls Computer Science: 40 Key Computer Science Concepts Caching Tutorial What every programmer should know about memory Введение в SOLID Consistent Hashing: Algorithmic Tradeoffs The Deadlock Empire The introduction to Reactive Programming you&amp;rsquo;ve been missing How Web Works Стажёр Вася и его истории об идемпотентности API Design patterns for humans Рефакторинг Гуру Databases Practical Guide to SQL Transaction Isolation Путешествие запроса Select через внутренности Постгреса Understanding EXPLAIN Useful PostgreSQL Queries and Commands PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s explain analyze made readable PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s explain analyze Гайд от Jepsen по моделям согласованности Database Fundamentals - крутое обьяснений Things You Should Know About Databases https://avestura.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Questions</title>
      <link>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/linux-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bege13mot.github.io/qa/linux-questions/</guid>
      <description>Questions from chassing/linux-sysadmin-interview-questions Inspired by collection of Linux SysAdm/DevOps interview questions with my answers&#xA;General Questions: What are the default ports used for SMTP,DNS,FTP,DHCP,SSH?&#xA;SMTP - 25 DNS - 53 FTP- 20(data transfer), 21(connection established) DHCP- 67/UDP(dhcp server) , 68/UDP(dhcp client) SSH - 22 What function does DNS play on a network?&#xA;The first place your computer looks is its local DNS cache, which stores information that your computer has recently retrieved.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
